# Keheliya Bandara Gallaba

2256, W 37th Ave, Vancouver, BC V6M 1P1, Canada

Email:<u>keheliya.gallaba@gmail.com</u> Site: <u>http://ece.ubc.ca/~kgallaba/</u>

Mobile: (604) 600-4669

#### **Profile**

Energetic, self-motivated technology enthusiast with an academic background of computer science & engineering, interested in exploring Business Process Modeling, data visualization, and Software Engineering. With a passion for reading and writing to make people's lives easier, better and happier using technology. Having experience contributing to Open Source software frameworks/platforms. I like to collaborate with people, make use of my problem solving and communication skills to achieve challenging goals.

## Education

- Master of Applied Science In Electrical & Computer Engineering
  at University of British Columbia, January 2014 Present (Supervised by Dr. Ali Mesbah)
- Bachelor of the Science of Engineering (specializing in Computer Science & Engineering)
  at Faculty of Engineering, University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka (2007-2011)
  - School education at *Royal College*, *Colombo*, *Sri Lanka*
  - Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP) in 2006
  - British Computer Society Professional Examinations (Certificate) in 2006

## Work Experience

- Teaching Assistant for EECE 310 Software Engineering at UBC (Winter 2013)
- Senior Software Engineer at WSO2 Inc. (*April 2013 November 2013*)
  - Member Integration Technologies Team
  - Working with WSO2 Business Process Server, Enterprise Service Bus, Identity Server & Governance Registry
- Software Engineer at WSO2 Inc. (December 2011- March 2013)
- Visiting Instructor at Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Moratuwa
  - CS 2212 Programming Challenge II (May 2011 September 2011)
  - CS 2202 Programming Challenge (September 2010 December 2010)
- Software Engineering Intern at WSO2 Inc. (February 2010 to August 2010)
  - Had experience working with WS-BPEL, Apache ODE and Eclipse plug-in development.
- Good at coding in Java, Javascript, CSS, HTML
  - Development Tools: Maven, Ant, Git, SVN, intellij IDEA
  - Average knowledge in C/C++, PHP, Python, Shell scripting
  - Loves to master R, Ruby, Haskell, AIR

- Github Profile: <a href="https://github.com/keheliya">https://github.com/keheliya</a>
- Experienced in: jQuery, D3.js, Node.js, Ruby on Rails
- Having an active web presence
  - Blogs : <a href="http://keheliya.blogpost.com">http://keheliya.blogpost.com</a>
- <a href="http://galpotha.wordpress.com">http://galpotha.wordpress.com</a>
- Microblog: <a href="http://twitter.com/keheliya">http://twitter.com/keheliya</a>
- http://visualguides.tumblr.com
- Possessing a Canadian open work permit

# **Contribution for Open Source Software**

- The Creator of 'SiyaBasScript' Mozilla Firefox / Google Chrome extensions which allowed viewing Non-Unicode Sinhala Language Content of Major News Sites on Unicode enabled computers. [http://code.google.com/p/siyabasscript/]
  - Manthan Award South Asia for e-Localization in December 2010 at New Delhi, India.
    [http://manthanaward.org/section\_full\_story.asp?id=968]
  - e-Swabhimani 2010 award for e-Localization at the National Best e-Content Awards.
- System Developer/Contributor for Gephi and GraphViz Open Source Information Visualization Projects
  - http://gephi.org/about/people/
  - <a href="http://www.loria.fr/~szathmar/off/projects/java/GraphVizAPI/index.php#credits">http://www.loria.fr/~szathmar/off/projects/java/GraphVizAPI/index.php#credits</a>
- Contributor in localization of FOSS projects including Ubuntu, Sugar Labs, GNOME and Miro
  since January 2008 *My Profile at Launchpad* [https://launchpad.net/~keheliya-gallaba]
- Google Summer of Code 2010 LDAP diagnostic tool plug-in to Apache Directory Studio
  - http://code.google.com/p/dirstudio-ldap-proxy/wiki/GoogleSummerOfCode2010Proposa
- Google Summer of Code 2011 The Gephi Consortium
  - Developed an automated build to fasten the release process of Gephi, open source graph visualization and manipulation software.
- Contributor in 'Levi' a native BPMN 2.0 execution engine, used to execute business process models that conform to the BPMN 2.0 specification
  - https://github.com/umashanthi/levi-project

## **Publications/Presentations**

- Levi A Workflow Engine using BPMN 2.0, co-author
  - In: Springer, Workshop on Cloud-enabled Business Process Management (CeBPM 2012) at 13th Intl. Conf. on Web Information System Engineering (WISE 2012), Nov 28-30, 2012, Paphos, Cyprus
- Levi A Business Process Management Engine using BPMN 2.0
  - Proceedings of the ERP Future 2012 (Springer Lecture Notes), Salzburg, Austria 2012.
    (forthcoming)
- Invited panelist on 'Social Inclusion & Localization through ICT tools' at "International Conference on Digital Content & Services"
  - Special Focus: Empowering rural masses through 3G/Wireless/Broadband December 2010 – New Delhi, India
- An analysis of BPMN 2.0 as a Business Process Execution Language

- o 17th ERU Research Symposium Colombo, Sri Lanka December 2011
- 'A Study of Cyber Warfare Associated with WikiLeaks'
  - Cyber Warfare Conference February 2011 Information Technology and Communications Engineering Sectional Committee of the Institution of Engineers, Sri Lanka
- Levi The Native BPMN 2.0 Execution Engine
  - CS&ES Conference 2011 University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka November 2011
- 'SiyaBasScript Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome Extension for converting web sites with non-Unicode Sinhala fonts to Unicode'
  - CSE Symposium April 2010

## Volunteer Experience

- Invited Speaker at FOSS/GSoC Awareness Session, University of Jaffna, January 2012
- Represented Sri Lanka at the EVOLVE International Conference in May 2008 Organized by AIESEC in Singapore, where Asia Pacific's corporates, NGOs and student leaders were brought together to discuss Social Entrepreneurship.
- · A Founder Contributor of 'The Gamer' Sri Lanka's first and only Gaming Magazine
  - http://www.facebook.com/gamermag
- Facilitated at 'Beyond the Camera Lens' The ten-day Children's Film Camp organized by the U.S. Embassy and the Galle Film Festival. (August 2009)
- Facilitated at Carsons Cumberbatch Annual Undergraduate Convention (Colombo, Sri Lanka, September 2008)
- Participation at the National Leadership Development Seminars 2007 and 2008 (four-day residential conferences) organized by AIESEC in Sri Lanka.

## Memberships in Associations, Clubs

- Student member of Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) and Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)
- Vice President (Information Systems & Communication) for Colombo South Local committee (UOM) of AIESEC in Sri Lanka (2008-2009)
- World Rank #96 at the IEEEXTREME Programming Competition 4.0 conducted by IEEE [http://www.ieeeuom.org/ieeextreme/24-story-behind-xtreme-40]
- Final round contestant at the Sri Lankan Selections of 47th International Mathematical Olympiad, Slovenia, 2006
- Bronze Medal at the Sri Lankan Physics Olympiad competition 2006 organized by the Institute of Physics, Sri Lanka
- High Distinction at the Australian National Chemistry Quiz -Junior Division in 2003 and Senior Division in 2005 - organized by Royal Australian Chemical Institute
- Won the award for Best Female Portrayal at the CSE DramaFest 2009 for character of Lady Bracknell in the drama 'The Importance of Being Earnest' by Oscar Wilde.
- Was a junior prefect in 2001 and a college steward in 2005 at Royal College, Colombo
- Was a member of the choir of Royal College, Colombo.
- Completed up to Grade V in Theory of Music Examinations conducted by the Institute of Western Music and Speech, Sri Lanka

## **Language Fluency**

- Pass with merit at 'Spoken English for speakers of other languages Grade II' conducted by Trinity College, London, August 1998
- Certificate in Business English University of Colombo, March 2007

## **Academic Referee**

Chandana Gamage, Ph.D.

chandag@uom.lk

Senior Lecturer,

Department of Computer Science and Engineering,

University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Contact No: +94112640387

## **Professional Referee**

Sanjiva Weerawarana, Ph.D.

sanjiva@wso2.com

Founder, Chairman & CEO; WSO2 Inc.

Founder, Director & Chief Scientist;

Lanka Software Foundation;

http://www.opensource.lk/

I hereby certify that the particulars furnished above as true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Keheliya Bandara Gallaba 2256, W 37th Ave, Vancouver, BC V6M 1P1, Canada